#### Contact

joseph.gefroh@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jgefroh (LinkedIn) www.jgefroh.com (Personal)

medium.com/@jgefroh (Blog)

## Top Skills

Leadership Management Programming

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

# Joseph Gefroh

Engineering Manager at Snap! Raise - We're hiring! Seattle, Washington

## Summary

My expertise is in helping teams execute and get things done.

I'm a highly experienced software engineer and manager with a knack for turning underperforming groups into highly productive teams.

Companies desperately need people who can both build the software and manage the teams building it.

That's me.

I really enjoy helping improve company cultures and teams. Sometimes that means helping people achieve their potential. Other times it means finding areas to improve the engineering process. Occasionally it means improving the code and building the software as a full-stack engineer.

I'm quite comfortable doing all three in both startup and enterprise environments!

Recently my work has focused on building software for team crowdfunding using Ruby on Rails and Vue.js. Previously I've led teams in building credit card processing gateways and enterprise software systems using a variety of different technologies.

I was also the technical co-founder of a startup that failed. I learned a lot of lessons from that experience!

#### SKILLS

- Engineering management
- ▷ Software engineering
- Management consulting
- ▶ Agile development
- Process improvement

### ◆ TECHNOLOGIES (EXPERIENCED)

- ▷ AngularJS 1
- ▷ Amazon Web Services (AWS) (EC2, ECR, IAM, S3, RDS, Route 53, CloudFront, CloudWatch)
- ▶ Bootstrap
- ▶ Bourbon
- ▶ Broccoli
- ▶ Brunch
- ▷ CSS
- ▶ Databases
- Docker / Docker Compose
- ▷ dokku
- ▷ Google Web Toolkit
- ⊳ Git
- ▷ Grunt
- ▷ Gulp
- ▶ Heroku
- ▶ HTML
- ▷ Java / Java EE (CDI, EJB, JAX-RS, JPA)
- ▶ Javascript
- ▶ Neat
- ▶ NGINX
- ▷ NoSQL (Redis, MongoDB)
- ▶ React
- ▶ Ruby / Ruby on Rails
- ▷ Sass
- ▷ SCSS
- ▷ Servers (JBoss, TomCat, TomEE, WebSphere, WebSphere Liberty)
- ▷ SQL (DB2, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL)
- > Vue.js
- ▶ Webpack

# Experience

Snap! Raise

6 months

**Engineering Manager** 

#### August 2018 - Present

Greater Seattle Area

#### ♠ ABOUT SNAP! RAISE (SNAP! MOBILE)

▷ Snap! Raise is a digital team fundraising platform built specifically to help make fundraising easy for coaches and students in school groups, teams, and clubs.

#### WHAT I DID

▶ Managed 3 engineering teams (9 engineers) simultaneously that were developing our core, revenue-generating products.

#### RESULTS

- ▷ Created internal training programs for team leads, managers, and engineers to provide management, tech, and leadership skills.
- ▶ Mentored and provided 1:1 training to team leads and engineers.
- ▶ Provided management consulting and leadership training to multiple team members.
- ▶ Improved stability, quality, and reliability of the codebase by prioritizing solid development practices and automated testing.
- ▶ Greatly improved engineering capabilities of teams by implementing effective agile engineering processes and facilitating communication.
- ▶ Initiated efforts to mature organization, including contributing to the development of a career ladder, cross-team processes, core values, documentation, etc.

# Lead Software Engineer

June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Greater Seattle Area

#### WHAT I DID

▶ Led the front-end engineering team of 3 on the front-end in our Snap! Raise division.

#### RESULTS

▷ Created a stable foundation for future development using Vue.js by architecting and developing architecture patterns and libraries.

▶ Mentored engineers, teaching solid development patterns and practices.

### Snap! Advance

Lead Software Engineer

November 2017 - June 2018 (8 months)

Greater Seattle Area

#### ♠ ABOUT SNAP! ADVANCE (SNAP! MOBILE)

▷ Snap! Advance is a donor management and digital fundraising platform built specifically for universities and colleges to run successful giving days.

#### WHAT I DID

▶ Led the engineering team of 4 in our Snap! Advance division.

#### RESULTS

- ▶ Improved platform's ability to handle higher load by an order of magnitude by resolving architecture and scaling issues.
- ▶ Tripled team's engineering velocity by implementing effective agile engineering processes.
- Met all scheduled quarterly delivery roadmaps.
- ▷ Programmed and architected various software features using Ruby on Rails / React / EmberJS / MongoDB.
- ▶ Mentored engineers, teaching solid development patterns and practices.

#### Jumpsuit Commerce

Advisor

September 2017 - January 2018 (5 months)

Honolulu, Hawaii

#### **♦** ABOUT JUMPSUIT COMMERCE

▶ Jumpsuit Commerce is a payments facilitator startup that provides financial services, credit card processing, and merchant processing services to companies, retailers, and non-profits.

#### WHAT I DID

▶ Advised founder and engineering team on engineering management issues and technical direction of company.

#### **Draft Fantasy**

Advisor

January 2017 - January 2018 (1 year 1 month)

London, United Kingdom

#### ABOUT DRAFT FANTASY

▶ Draft Fantasy is a market leader in real money and free to play fantasy football in the UK, with Premier League & Champions League draft & auction style leagues.

#### WHAT I DID

▶ Advised the CEO on engineering management issues and the development and execution of software engineering plans.

Jumpsuit Commerce Lead Software Engineer September 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 1 month) Hawaijan Islands

#### WHAT I DID

▷ I led, managed, and directed engineering at the company, decided the organization's technical direction as a member of the executive team, and programmed great software products as member of the engineering team.

#### RESULTS

- ▶ Built, managed, and led high-performing engineering team.
- ▶ Rescued failing project on the verge of shutting down the company, rebuilding it within a month and turning it into the company's flagship software product.
- ▶ Architected, programmed, and delivered multiple greenfield SaaS products that now process millions of dollars a month using Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, Javascript, Docker, AWS.
- ▶ Increased development speed, going from monthly deploys to daily deploys of new features, by establishing effective development practices, mentoring developers, and creating reusable libraries.
- ▶ Achieved PCI compliance as a payments facilitator by establishing secure engineering and operating practices.

Built highly cohesive team and company culture.

hnl.io

Co-founder / CTO

August 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 1 month)

Hawaiian Islands

#### ABOUT HNL.IO

▶ hnl.io was a startup founded by myself and James Wang to to unify Hawaii's fractured and silo'd tech and startup communities and act as a welcoming gateway to newcomers, promoting growth, engagement, and the overall health of the local tech and startup economy.

#### WHAT I DID

- ▷ I led the engineering team on the product, managed the team, and handled the company's day-to-day operations.
- ▷ I led development of our event and group platform using Ruby on Rails and AngularJS.

#### OUR VISION

▶ We envisioned a platform run and managed by the community that would provide a a one-stop shop for information related to Hawaii's events, startups, companies, and communities. It would solve the problem of information diaspora that these communities suffered from - people often found out about events long after they finished, and newcomers to the Hawaii tech scene were unable to find even basic information on what was available to them without first somehow becoming a part of the network. Hawaii is very much dependent on "who-you-know" as a culture, and this was both intimidating and unwelcoming to newcomers to the community.

#### OUR SUCCESSES

▶ hnl.io was able to secure a \$100,000 seed round, and within 3 months our team launched the product, seeing active usage with hundreds of unique visitors a week - great for our small community. Many people we met afterwards expressed their thanks for hnl.io - they were able to get a foot-in-the-door to these unintentionally exclusive networks through the platform and personal guidance.

#### OUR FAILURES

▶ Despite securing some key sponsorships to continue operating for another year, we were unable to articulate a viable business model that engaged the

existing community to contribute and create a lasting impact, and we ceased operating the product in August 2017.

Draft Fantasy Investor January 2017 - January 2017 (1 month) London, United Kingdom

eWorld Enterprise Solutions, Inc.
Tech Lead (title: Systems Analyst)
August 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 1 month)
Honolulu. Hawaii

#### ♠ ABOUT EWORLD ENTERPRISE SOLUTIONS

▶ eWorld Enterprise Solutions is a consulting firm that provides software engineering and management consulting services to the private and public sector.

#### WHAT I DID

▶ I helped eWorld modernize their development practices, led engineering teams on several successful projects as the de-facto tech lead, and created a foundation for future iterative improvement.

#### RESULTS

- ▷ Established effective development processes to handle both greenfield and legacy enterprise software development.
- ▶ Architected and programmed everything from internal frameworks to document workflow engines to timesheet routing software to reusable authorization engines.
- ▶ Spearheaded multiple initiatives that modernized various development practices and grew a team culture of collaboration, open communication, and continuous improvement.
- ▷ Initiatives included:
- ✓ using agile development practices (stand-up meetings, pair programming, peer code reviews)
- ✓ switching to AngularJS from GWT to improve development speed
- ✓ championing Git/Github instead of SVN to support dynamic development workflows

- √ emphasizing UX design to improve software usability
- √ conducting security and architecture reviews to decrease risk exposure
- ✓ mentoring developers in technologies, development practices, and team dynamics
- ✓ teaching technologies like AngularJS, Java EE, GWT, and Git
- √ introducing and leading lunch learning sessions
- √ emphasizing and providing resources for professional development

### Hawaii Pacific University

IT Technician (title: Technical Analyst Assistant) January 2011 - February 2013 (2 years 2 months)

Honolulu, Hawaii

#### **♦** ABOUT HAWAII PACIFIC UNIVERSITY

▶ Hawaii Pacific University is the State of Hawaii's leading private nonprofit college.

#### WHAT I DID

- ▷ Resolved 1000+ hardware, software, and network issues in an enterprise environment.
- ▶ Resolved users' various issues while handling incoming calls and walk-ins.
- ▶ Trained and mentored peers in fulfilling relevant job responsibilities.
- ▷ Created reports for management by analyzing datasets with 200,000+ elements.

# Education

Hawaii Pacific University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science (2009 - 2012)